ALEKSANDR FEDCHENKO

PROFILE

I'm a back-end developer and DevOps engineer. I'm 30 years old. I have an experience in web (monoliths and microsevices) and embedded software development, infrastructure deploying and system administration. I have a research experience in the field of control theory (satellite power supplies and UAV) and have multiple patents and publications. I have good communication skills, and I held several senior positions previously. Currently I'm interested in highload and ML projects that can give me an opportunity to acquire new professional competencies and to work with talented people.

EXPERIENCE

B2Basket.ru

Moscow, RU

TEAM LEAD

Sep 2019 - Nov 2020

- Design of E-commerce marketplace integration platform
- Cloud infrastructure deployment and service administration
- Development of marketplace and pricing platform modules
- Research activity (ML-algorithms for data matching services)
- IT department planning and management



Zhukovsky, RU

NPP Strela (НПП Стрела)

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb 2018 - Sep 2019

- Development of UAV diagnostics software and real-time operating system
- Design of ground control station software
- UAV mathematical model derivation and digital filters calculation
- Research and synthesis of control systems (H∞ and adaptive ML controllers)
- Development department management













Autonomous Energetics (Автономная Энергетика)

Krasnoyarsk, RU Feb 2011 - Feb 2018

RESEARCH ENGINEER

- Design of electronic load embedded software
- Development of power supply test stand interface
- Research activity (charge-discharge devices for spacecraft battery testing)
- Analysis and synthesis of control systems for switched-mode power supplies
- Circuit design and test stand assembling















EDUCATION

MSc in Electrical Engineering (Motion Control Systems and Navigation) Reshetnev Siberian State University of Science and Technology Sep 2015 - Jul 2017

Specialist Degree in Electrical Engineering (Aircraft Control Systems) Siberian State Aerospace University Sep 2008 - Jul 2014



+7 929 335 61 48

mail@alekfed.com

@alekfed

alekfed.com

Moscow, RU

Fmacs

SKILLS =

Languages: Python, Go, JS/TS, SQL, Bash, C++, Common Lisp Frameworks: Django, FastAPI, Fiber, Apollo, Flask, Keras, React DB & MQ: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ DevOps: Kubernetes, Helm, Nix, GitLab CI, Ansible, Terraform Other: LaTeX, Inkscape, KiCad,

LANGUAGES =

Russian Native English C1 Japanese N5

PATENTS ====

RU153595U1 RU154432U1 RU153595U1

INTERESTS

Movies Mathematics Music Cooking Design Tennis